<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>weeknotes on nondescryptid</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/tags/weeknotes/</link><description>Recent content in weeknotes on nondescryptid</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:36:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomoe.asia/tags/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weeknote 15</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/weeknote-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 12:36:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/weeknote-15/</guid><description>This week, I
made a ring using a baby tooth I found while unpacking from moving. I kept most of my baby teeth in a ziploc bag (not sure why I did that, but I was pretty weird even as a kid). Google says people have 20 baby teeth, and I have 18 still with me, so that&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good yield. Molars are good for rings because they&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a flat base and a rectangular shape.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week, I</p>
<ul>
<li>made <a href="https://kopiti.am/@nondescryptid/112256968366180370">a ring using a baby tooth</a> I found while unpacking from moving. I kept most of my baby teeth in a ziploc bag (not sure why I did that, but I was pretty weird even as a kid). Google says people have 20 baby teeth, and I have 18 still with me, so that&rsquo;s a pretty good yield. Molars are good for rings because they&rsquo;ve got quite a flat base and a rectangular shape. Could try other methods of setting the stone like a bezel set or prong set when I get access to the tools needed. I haven&rsquo;t really figured out what to do with incisors - maybe I&rsquo;ll get screw eye rings and turn them into charms for a necklace/bracelet.</li>
<li>first encountered and started using <a href="https://pypi.org/project/memory-profiler/"><code>memory-profiler</code></a>. I came across some code that normalized JSON on a per-entry basis. <code>pandas.json_normalize</code> accepts JSON and returns a dataframe. This code called json_normalize for 1 entry, and then concatenates it to the existing dataframe. This ended up taking really long (&gt;8 minutes for 35000+ entries) and I wanted to compare how much time and memory it&rsquo;d take if one did the operation in batches of 5000 entries instead. <code>memory-profiler</code> was very helpful for this =)</li>
<li>helped my friend fix their Mid-2015 A1502 Macbook Pro - we replaced the speakers and the Airport card. I realised I could help because I&rsquo;ve done a speaker replacement on my own A1502. This repair was more special because my own A1502&rsquo;s just more of a backup laptop, but my friend&rsquo;s A1502 is their only laptop. Starting it up and being able to play music and access the Internet was honestly a really joyful moment.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Weeknote 14</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/weeknote-14/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 23:48:18 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/weeknote-14/</guid><description>This marks the first week of being temporarily free-range. I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out the right term for it yet. I joked about this a bit 2 weeks ago, but &amp;ldquo;temporarily free-range&amp;rdquo; is my top contender for now. I&amp;rsquo;m avoiding calling it a sabbatical because it reminds me too much of tenured faculty, and &amp;ldquo;microdosing retirement&amp;rdquo; sounds a bit too laid back. What matters (and what&amp;rsquo;s kind of scary) about this time is that nobody can tell me what to do.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This marks the first week of being temporarily free-range. I haven&rsquo;t figured out the right term for it yet. I <a href="https://kopiti.am/@nondescryptid/112145128076061313">joked about this a bit</a> 2 weeks ago, but &ldquo;temporarily free-range&rdquo; is my top contender for now. I&rsquo;m avoiding calling it a sabbatical because it reminds me too much of tenured faculty, and &ldquo;microdosing retirement&rdquo; sounds a bit too laid back. What matters (and what&rsquo;s kind of scary) about this time is that nobody can tell me what to do.</p>
<p>In light of this, I&rsquo;ve started off my first week by just letting myself be a degenerate. I&rsquo;ve just been sleeping a lot - more than I have in a long time. This must be how cats feel when they curl up to take a nap in the middle of the day.</p>
<p>If I had to choose a word for the week, I&rsquo;d choose &ldquo;maintenance&rdquo;. If I had to choose 8 words, it would be &ldquo;doing things I&rsquo;ve avoided for the longest time&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve spent a lot of time this week sleeping, doing laundry, unpacking from the move, taking care of plants, and sharpening knives (sidenote: I plan on going to a knife shop next week to learn how to properly sharpen a knife and also level the whetstone I&rsquo;m using. It was my grandfather&rsquo;s, so it might very well be older than me). Haven&rsquo;t done a lot of programming-related work besides trying to learn SQL. I&rsquo;ve somehow avoided it for the longest time,like going to the dentist - but I have overcome that this week and now have very clean teeth.</p>
<p>And since no update is ever complete without some minor bug introduction - I updated my Hugo version and now my <code>date published / reading time</code> sections are borked, but I won&rsquo;t let it stop me from yapping online and publishing my posts anyway.</p>
<p>Happy update: My website actually looks fine! Hooray! But the problem happens when I use <code>hugo serve</code> locally.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>