<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>35mm on nondescryptid</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/tags/35mm/</link><description>Recent content in 35mm on nondescryptid</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 01:45:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomoe.asia/tags/35mm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 - a Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 by any other name would shoot the same</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-08-06-fuji-zoom-cardia-super-115/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 01:45:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-08-06-fuji-zoom-cardia-super-115/</guid><description>TL;DR: These two cameras are the same. If you can’t find manuals for the Fuji, use this Samsung one: https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf (Credits to Michael Butkus Jr, who&amp;rsquo;s been archiving camera manuals since 1997 with https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html)
What ever happened? I had thrifted some cameras, and was unable to find any manuals for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 I got. It has a ton of modes like Fuzzy, Portrait, and something that looked like a self-timer and interval shooting.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TL;DR: These two cameras are the same. If you can’t find manuals for the Fuji, use this Samsung one: <a href="https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf">https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf</a> (Credits to <a href="https://www.butkus.org/">Michael Butkus Jr</a>, who&rsquo;s been archiving camera manuals since 1997 with <a href="https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html">https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html</a>)</p>
<h1 id="what-ever-happened">What ever happened?</h1>
<p>I had thrifted some cameras, and was unable to find any manuals for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 I got. It has a ton of modes like Fuzzy, Portrait, and something that looked like a self-timer and interval shooting. The problem was that I didn’t actually know how they operated.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/fuji-super-115" alt="Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115, front view"  />
</p>
<p>I came across <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytvjiX_RVSA">a video by ThisRetroLife</a> saying that the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 is actually a clone of a Samsung Fuzzyzoom 1050 (also known as Zoom 1050 AF/ Maxima Zoom 105).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/thisretrolife-title-screenshot" alt="Screenshot of the title of ThisRetroLife&amp;rsquo;s video"  />
</p>
<p>However, the Samsung Fuzzyzoom 1050&rsquo;s maximum focal length, at 105mm (see <a href="https://quirkyguywithacamera.blogspot.com/2016/12/capable-but-complicated-samsung-maxima.html">Adam Paul’s review</a>), is 10mm short of the Fuji 115. It&rsquo;s close, but not quite.</p>
<p>I ended up looking for Samsung cameras with a focal length of up to 115mm. A rudimentary Google search gave me <a href="https://www.35mmc.com/22/10/2021/samsung-slim-zoom-1150-review/">Shawn Granton’s review of the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150</a>. Delightful! They&rsquo;re truly clones of each other.</p>
<p>Then, after trying to look up mentions of the Fuji Cardia Super 115 on Reddit, I realised that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnalogCommunity/comments/rtnbk0/comment/hqtob9g/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">u/marakh had come to the same conclusion 2 years ago</a>, and I could’ve skipped a lot of this sleuthing if I had scoured Reddit more thoroughly to begin with:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/samsung-slim-zoom-comment" alt="Comment from u/marakh observing that the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 is a clone of the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150"  />
</p>
<p>Typical experience of being online where I think that I&rsquo;ve done something original, then find someone else who&rsquo;s done the same thing years earlier. Tough.</p>
<p>Just for fun, I decided to try and see if I could find original prices for the Samsung and Fuji. I didn&rsquo;t manage to find one for the Fuji (please let me know if you do), but did manage to find a mention of the Samsung. The Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 used to retail for USD$599 (according to the June 1994 issue of Popular Photography<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/1994-pop-photography-samsung-slim-zoom-1150#center" alt="Listing from the June 1994 issue of Popular Photography stating the original retail price"  />
</p>
<p>It’s quite remarkable how these cameras have depreciated over the years. A Samsung Slim Zoom in Singapore has been sold for SGD65 (listing here). I got the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 for JPY550 (SGD5-ish) in the junk section of a hardware thrift shop in Japan.</p>
<p>I guess I can’t complain about how point and shoots you can get off the shelf these days like the <a href="https://www.kodak.com/en/consumer/product/cameras/film/m35">Kodak M35</a> feel plasticky and cheap, because they really <em>are</em> cheap (relative to the original cost of the cameras I’m comparing them to).</p>
<h1 id="will-it-shoot">Will it shoot?</h1>
<p>The next thing to figure out is – will the <a href="https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf">manual</a> for the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 also work for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115?</p>
<h2 id="testing-the-multi-exposure-mode">Testing the multi-exposure mode</h2>
<p>I don’t have a Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 to conduct a point-by-point comparison, but the Samsung manual seems to hold up in relation to the multi-exposure mode. I found multi-exposure to be the mode that’s easiest to test – I don’t know how to assess if Fuzzy or Portrait work the way they’re supposed to, and I’m too stingy to test Interval and Continuous shooting.</p>
<p>The manual at page 23 states that you’re not restricted to double exposure – you can do as many exposures as you like, as long as you set the mode to multi-exposure again after each shot. This is a feature I wouldn’t have ever deduced independently.</p>
<p>I set multi-exposure 3 times for a total of 4 exposures, but I don’t think the final one showed up properly. However, you can still discern at least 3 exposures – (1) a shot of the ceiling, (2) a bulletin board with a note pinned on it, and (3) a cupboard with a jug.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940001" alt="Multiple-exposure mode on the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115"  />

<em>At least 3 exposures</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940017" alt="Double exposure of trees and a person standing against a wall"  />
</p>
<p><em>A good old double exposure, featuring <a href="https://www.instagram.com/midtonegrey/?hl=en">Sroyon/@midtonegrey</a> (you should read his articles on <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=35mmc+sroyon&amp;oq=35mmc+sroyon&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.1493j0j1&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">35mmc</a> and <a href="">Casual Photophile</a>)</em><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<h2 id="other-photos">Other photos</h2>
<p>Sometimes I wonder how much I should write with future people in mind &ndash; like stating more details about time and place in my photos, in case there&rsquo;s some kid from the future who needs to do a history project about wayward, bumbling 20-somethings living in Singapore in the 2020s. But I digress.</p>
<p>These were taken sometime in July 2023 with Kodak ColorPlus 200. I take photos, but don&rsquo;t really consider myself a photographer - Right now, my fascination lies with thrifting and testing these little machines as opposed to committing to the craft of composing and thinking about images. I feel bad since I feel like I&rsquo;m being a bit mercenary and not treating these cameras as nicely as I should.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940002" alt="Shot in the Singapore Botanic Gardens"  />

<em>Singapore Botanic Gardens</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940024" alt="CHIJMES on an overcast day"  />

<em>CHIJMES on an overcast day</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940026" alt="Flash illuminating part of a road at night"  />

<em>Wandering about near Mt Faber</em></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://books.google.com.sg/books?id=nDAVsvMUYksC&amp;pg=PA57&amp;dq=samsung+slim+zoom+1150+599&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiRyvS6mJ-AAxUayjgGHcIqB5IQ6AF6BAgEEAI#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false"><em>Popular Photography</em>, June 1994 issue at page 57</a>. Also today I learnt that I can center images in markdown by adding <code>#center</code> after the path&hellip;&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Posted with Sroyon&rsquo;s consent, as all photos of people&rsquo;s faces should be. I have a weird gripe about this because my university posted photos of me on the school&rsquo;s website without asking. I used to think about doing street photography, but I&rsquo;m too awkward to approach strangers in public.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>