<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>35mm on nondescryptid</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/tags/35mm/</link><description>Recent content in 35mm on nondescryptid</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 21:22:09 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomoe.asia/tags/35mm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raynox ME-606: Great for people, or simulating astigmatism</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/raynox-me-606/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 21:22:09 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/raynox-me-606/</guid><description>[updated 2 Jul with an additional photo]
I got the Raynox ME-606 in a random Hard-Off junk section (more precisely, Hard-Off at Hirata in Matsumoto) for the princely sum of 300 yen, with no real guarantees about whether it would work. This was before I wisened up and started bringing my own batteries for thrifting cameras, so all I knew was that it had corroded battery contacts and a battery flap that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t shut.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[updated 2 Jul with an additional photo]</p>
<p>I got the Raynox ME-606 in a random Hard-Off junk section (more precisely, Hard-Off at Hirata in Matsumoto) for the princely sum of 300 yen, with no real guarantees about whether it would work. This was before I wisened up and started bringing my own batteries for thrifting cameras, so all I knew was that it had corroded battery contacts and a battery flap that wouldn&rsquo;t shut.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/IMG_5345" alt="Photo of Raynox ME-606 camera with a price tag of 300 JPY"  />
</p>
<p>A lot of my interests can be described as &ldquo;deliberate inconvenience&rdquo; (shooting with film, repairing appliances, taking random detours on walks). To keep this up, I got home and cleaned the corrosion with white vinegar&hellip;and it worked (shutter + film advance + flash worked)! I also had to tape the battery flap shut since the latch had broken off.</p>
<p>The next step was to test it with an actual roll of film. This ended up being somewhat high-stakes as most of the photos were shot on vacation, but I&rsquo;m pleased to tell you that the camera actually does work.</p>
<p>This camera has no settings to fiddle with. You don&rsquo;t even get to choose when the flash fires. It&rsquo;ll fire when it feels like it, and also takes a few seconds to charge between shots. There are no zoom or focusing options. All you really have control over is what you&rsquo;re trying to shoot.</p>
<h1 id="why-i-think-this-has-a-fixed-focal-length">Why I think this has a fixed focal length</h1>
<h2 id="doing-well-on-people--things-close-by">Doing well on people / things close by</h2>
<p>Based on how the photos turned out, I think this has a fixed focal length that&rsquo;s best for shooting people and things that are fairly close by (e.g. 0.5 metres - 2m).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740025" alt="Various potted plants on a table"  />
</p>
<p>This is a photo of a friend&rsquo;s desk. The items in the background appear clearest.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740037" alt="Photo of a wall at The Projector cinema in Singapore with various director/actors&amp;rsquo; signatures and messages"  />
</p>
<p>Photo of the wall at The Projector&rsquo;s Cineleisure outlet, with messages from various creatives who&rsquo;ve performed or had their work screened there. This includes Nicole Midori Woodford (director) and Mihaya Shirata (lead actress, who plays Ami in the film) from Last Shadow After First Light, and Atsuko Okatsuka (comedian). The light leak here was pretty serendipitous as I opened the film compartment a few shots in, as I wasn&rsquo;t sure if the film was even advancing. Then I shut the compartment and continued shooting, and I guess this is where the film was partially exposed and partially intact. :) This was done at a distance of about 1m.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740031" alt="Photo of a person with long hair smiling next to a wall of autographs"  />
</p>
<p>This photo was taken about 1.5m away. Things are still quite clear here.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1719856703/raynox%20me-606/IMG_0725.jpg" alt="Photo of a person wearing a blue shirt seated behind a table, taking a sip from a wine glass"  />
</p>
<p>This was about 1m away at most, since it was taken across a table.</p>
<h2 id="not-so-clear-on-landscapes-but-this-is-a-matter-of-personal-taste">Not so clear on landscapes (but this is a matter of personal taste)</h2>
<p>As we get further, things get dreamier/blurrier. I guess this depends on the effect you&rsquo;re going for. As someone with astigmatism, these photos will probably help others empathise with my bad eyesight.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740028" alt="Battersea Arts Centres"  />
</p>
<p>Battersea Arts Centre</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740019" alt="Apartments near Battersea Power Station"  />
</p>
<p>Apartments near Battersea Power Station</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/001639740020" alt="Person walking on a path at Holland Park. The path appears to curve and is framed by trees."  />
</p>
<p>Holland Park</p>
<h1 id="parting-thoughts">Parting thoughts</h1>
<p>This camera really surprised me as I wasn&rsquo;t expecting it to work at all. Think it&rsquo;d do best as a camera for covering parties as it 1. has flash, 2. was really cheap (so I won&rsquo;t be precious about it), and 3. seems to do well on close-mid distance shots.</p>
<p>Another happy side effect is that I&rsquo;m less nervous about decorating it (would never do this with my Konica C35 EF or a Rollei 35T&hellip;). I have a whole bunch of stickers from when I was a kid and had a huge stationery shopping problem. It felt like I was saving them for some imaginary situation that never happened, so&hellip; I&rsquo;m learning to just use the nice thing instead of waiting for the &ldquo;right&rdquo; time to use it.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/raynox%20me-606/IMG_0742" alt="Rayno ME-606 decorated with bird stickers"  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>5 Frames with the Konica TZ-635 &amp; Kodak Gold 200</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-09-04-konica-tz635/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 22:47:19 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-09-04-konica-tz635/</guid><description>The strange thing about cameras is that brands keep calling the same thing by different names. Why can&amp;rsquo;t we just have a unique identifier for each thing that exists? It&amp;rsquo;s like how the Canon EOS 750D is also called the Rebel T6i (see Wikipedia).
The Konica TZ-635 is no different - It appears to be called the Konica Zoom FR 635 too (like in this Youtube video by Meracasee or this random ebay listing).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The strange thing about cameras is that brands keep calling the same thing by different names. Why can&rsquo;t we just have a unique identifier for each thing that exists? It&rsquo;s like how the Canon EOS 750D is also called the Rebel T6i (see <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Canon_EOS_750D#:~:text=The%20Canon%20EOS%20750D%2C%20known,Canon%20on%20February%206%2C%202015">Wikipedia</a>).</p>
<p>The Konica TZ-635 is no different - It appears to be called the Konica Zoom FR 635 too (like in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g1YJx2lwB4g">Youtube video by Meracasee</a> or this <a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/165295050428">random ebay listing</a>).</p>
<p>There might be many Konica TZ-635s (or FR-635s) in the world, but this one is mine (until further notice).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/konica%20tz635/konica-tz635" alt=""  />
</p>
<p>I found it in the Kyoto-Katsura outlet of Hard Off (a Japanese chain that sells used electronics) for JPY2200 (about SGD20.36). Cameras in the junk section are usually untested, but this one happened to be tested! The sticker says that the shutter and flash are working, but the camera has not actually been tested with a roll of film. I tested the camera myself with the batteries I&rsquo;d brought along and confirmed that the sticker was telling the truth.</p>
<p>Besides the problem with names, film cameras also face a bit of an archival problem &ndash; manuals aren&rsquo;t always available.</p>
<p>Whenever I can&rsquo;t find manuals for my exact camera model (like the Fuji Super 115), I try to find others that kinda look like it. In this case, the manual for the Konica Z-Up 60 will do. The buttons/interface are arranged the same as the TZ-635, even though the front of the camera looks very different.</p>
<p>Someone is selling a <a href="https://www.camera-manual.com/konica-z-up-60-manual-6074">printed copy of the manual for USD13.95</a>, but you can get a free online copy if you&rsquo;re willing to look at some Japanese by going on <a href="http://gizport.jp/manual/1860464/?id=47573">gizport</a>. If you know Korean, you can watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g1YJx2lwB4g">Meracasee&rsquo;s video</a> where they go through the features of this camera.</p>
<h1 id="things-to-note">Things to note</h1>
<p>This is a TL;DR of the Japanese Z-Up 60 manual and my own experience.</p>
<ul>
<li>This uses AA batteries</li>
<li>Lens: 35mm f/5.8 - 60mm f/9.5</li>
<li>Takes ISO 100-400 film</li>
<li>Distance:
<ul>
<li>For regular shooting: 1.60m to infinity (35mm) / 2.40m to infinity (60mm)</li>
<li>Flash: 1.00m-2.60m / 1.30m - 2.50m (based on ISO400 colour negative film)</li>
<li>Macro (Manual says &ldquo;Close-up&rdquo;): 0.50m - 0.80m / 0.55m - 0.70m</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Flash is automatic and cannot be turned off unless you set it to Landscape mode</li>
<li>Self-timer mode: The timer lasts for 10 seconds. The indicator light will flash for 7 seconds, and then the flash itself will flash for 3 seconds before the shutter is activated.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="photos">Photos</h1>
<p>Shot with Kodak Gold 200</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1693839151/konica%20tz635/people_censored.jpg" alt="Photo of a woman seated next to a man indoors, by the dining table"  />

Sunglasses and mask were drawn on courtesy of me and my laptop trackpad.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1693839183/konica%20tz635/001364180021.jpg" alt="Signboard saying &amp;ldquo;coming soon&amp;rdquo;"  />
</p>
<p>I just found it kind of funny that this was positioned right in front of a road. I nearly walked onto the road because I was trying to get a better look at it. Perhaps &ldquo;coming soon&rdquo; refers to oncoming cars.
<img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1693839174/konica%20tz635/001364180016.jpg" alt="Kousaka restaurant"  />

Autofocus is a hit-or-miss thing. This one didn&rsquo;t focus quite well, but most photos are a hit for me. I&rsquo;m not very fussed about images being perfect - if I did, I wouldn&rsquo;t be using film or point-and-shoots&hellip;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1693839189/konica%20tz635/001364180020.jpg" alt="Steps and a red brick building"  />
</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/v1693839203/konica%20tz635/001364180027.jpg" alt="Blurry shot"  />

Random blurry shot that I must&rsquo;ve accidentally taken.</p>
<h1 id="thoughts">Thoughts</h1>
<p>I really, really like this camera and I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ll be selling it. Its build is solid enough that I can throw it into my bag without having to worry if it&rsquo;ll survive. I&rsquo;m happy with the limited sets of features. I like this more than the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 15, where you can deactivate flash but it takes 6 presses of the MODE button.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 - a Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 by any other name would shoot the same</title><link>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-08-06-fuji-zoom-cardia-super-115/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 01:45:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://tomoe.asia/posts/2023-08-06-fuji-zoom-cardia-super-115/</guid><description>TL;DR: These two cameras are the same. If you can’t find manuals for the Fuji, use this Samsung one: https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf (Credits to Michael Butkus Jr, who&amp;rsquo;s been archiving camera manuals since 1997 with https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html)
What ever happened? I had thrifted some cameras, and was unable to find any manuals for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 I got. It has a ton of modes like Fuzzy, Portrait, and something that looked like a self-timer and interval shooting.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TL;DR: These two cameras are the same. If you can’t find manuals for the Fuji, use this Samsung one: <a href="https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf">https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf</a> (Credits to <a href="https://www.butkus.org/">Michael Butkus Jr</a>, who&rsquo;s been archiving camera manuals since 1997 with <a href="https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html">https://butkus.org/chinon/index.html</a>)</p>
<h1 id="what-ever-happened">What ever happened?</h1>
<p>I had thrifted some cameras, and was unable to find any manuals for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 I got. It has a ton of modes like Fuzzy, Portrait, and something that looked like a self-timer and interval shooting. The problem was that I didn’t actually know how they operated.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/fuji-super-115" alt="Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115, front view"  />
</p>
<p>I came across <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ytvjiX_RVSA">a video by ThisRetroLife</a> saying that the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 is actually a clone of a Samsung Fuzzyzoom 1050 (also known as Zoom 1050 AF/ Maxima Zoom 105).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/thisretrolife-title-screenshot" alt="Screenshot of the title of ThisRetroLife&amp;rsquo;s video"  />
</p>
<p>However, the Samsung Fuzzyzoom 1050&rsquo;s maximum focal length, at 105mm (see <a href="https://quirkyguywithacamera.blogspot.com/2016/12/capable-but-complicated-samsung-maxima.html">Adam Paul’s review</a>), is 10mm short of the Fuji 115. It&rsquo;s close, but not quite.</p>
<p>I ended up looking for Samsung cameras with a focal length of up to 115mm. A rudimentary Google search gave me <a href="https://www.35mmc.com/22/10/2021/samsung-slim-zoom-1150-review/">Shawn Granton’s review of the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150</a>. Delightful! They&rsquo;re truly clones of each other.</p>
<p>Then, after trying to look up mentions of the Fuji Cardia Super 115 on Reddit, I realised that <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AnalogCommunity/comments/rtnbk0/comment/hqtob9g/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">u/marakh had come to the same conclusion 2 years ago</a>, and I could’ve skipped a lot of this sleuthing if I had scoured Reddit more thoroughly to begin with:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/samsung-slim-zoom-comment" alt="Comment from u/marakh observing that the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 is a clone of the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150"  />
</p>
<p>Typical experience of being online where I think that I&rsquo;ve done something original, then find someone else who&rsquo;s done the same thing years earlier. Tough.</p>
<p>Just for fun, I decided to try and see if I could find original prices for the Samsung and Fuji. I didn&rsquo;t manage to find one for the Fuji (please let me know if you do), but did manage to find a mention of the Samsung. The Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 used to retail for USD$599 (according to the June 1994 issue of Popular Photography<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>).</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/1994-pop-photography-samsung-slim-zoom-1150#center" alt="Listing from the June 1994 issue of Popular Photography stating the original retail price"  />
</p>
<p>It’s quite remarkable how these cameras have depreciated over the years. A Samsung Slim Zoom in Singapore has been sold for SGD65 (listing here). I got the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115 for JPY550 (SGD5-ish) in the junk section of a hardware thrift shop in Japan.</p>
<p>I guess I can’t complain about how point and shoots you can get off the shelf these days like the <a href="https://www.kodak.com/en/consumer/product/cameras/film/m35">Kodak M35</a> feel plasticky and cheap, because they really <em>are</em> cheap (relative to the original cost of the cameras I’m comparing them to).</p>
<h1 id="will-it-shoot">Will it shoot?</h1>
<p>The next thing to figure out is – will the <a href="https://cameramanuals.org/samsung/samsung_af-slim-zoom-e-s.pdf">manual</a> for the Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 also work for the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115?</p>
<h2 id="testing-the-multi-exposure-mode">Testing the multi-exposure mode</h2>
<p>I don’t have a Samsung Slim Zoom 1150 to conduct a point-by-point comparison, but the Samsung manual seems to hold up in relation to the multi-exposure mode. I found multi-exposure to be the mode that’s easiest to test – I don’t know how to assess if Fuzzy or Portrait work the way they’re supposed to, and I’m too stingy to test Interval and Continuous shooting.</p>
<p>The manual at page 23 states that you’re not restricted to double exposure – you can do as many exposures as you like, as long as you set the mode to multi-exposure again after each shot. This is a feature I wouldn’t have ever deduced independently.</p>
<p>I set multi-exposure 3 times for a total of 4 exposures, but I don’t think the final one showed up properly. However, you can still discern at least 3 exposures – (1) a shot of the ceiling, (2) a bulletin board with a note pinned on it, and (3) a cupboard with a jug.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940001" alt="Multiple-exposure mode on the Fuji Zoom Cardia Super 115"  />

<em>At least 3 exposures</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940017" alt="Double exposure of trees and a person standing against a wall"  />
</p>
<p><em>A good old double exposure, featuring <a href="https://www.instagram.com/midtonegrey/?hl=en">Sroyon/@midtonegrey</a> (you should read his articles on <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=35mmc+sroyon&amp;oq=35mmc+sroyon&amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.1493j0j1&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">35mmc</a> and <a href="">Casual Photophile</a>)</em><sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<h2 id="other-photos">Other photos</h2>
<p>Sometimes I wonder how much I should write with future people in mind &ndash; like stating more details about time and place in my photos, in case there&rsquo;s some kid from the future who needs to do a history project about wayward, bumbling 20-somethings living in Singapore in the 2020s. But I digress.</p>
<p>These were taken sometime in July 2023 with Kodak ColorPlus 200. I take photos, but don&rsquo;t really consider myself a photographer - Right now, my fascination lies with thrifting and testing these little machines as opposed to committing to the craft of composing and thinking about images. I feel bad since I feel like I&rsquo;m being a bit mercenary and not treating these cameras as nicely as I should.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940002" alt="Shot in the Singapore Botanic Gardens"  />

<em>Singapore Botanic Gardens</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940024" alt="CHIJMES on an overcast day"  />

<em>CHIJMES on an overcast day</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://res.cloudinary.com/dezwnhp01/image/upload/f_auto,q_auto/v1/fuji%20zoom%20cardia%20super%20115%20with%20kodak%20colorplus/001381940026" alt="Flash illuminating part of a road at night"  />

<em>Wandering about near Mt Faber</em></p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="https://books.google.com.sg/books?id=nDAVsvMUYksC&amp;pg=PA57&amp;dq=samsung+slim+zoom+1150+599&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=2ahUKEwiRyvS6mJ-AAxUayjgGHcIqB5IQ6AF6BAgEEAI#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false"><em>Popular Photography</em>, June 1994 issue at page 57</a>. Also today I learnt that I can center images in markdown by adding <code>#center</code> after the path&hellip;&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Posted with Sroyon&rsquo;s consent, as all photos of people&rsquo;s faces should be. I have a weird gripe about this because my university posted photos of me on the school&rsquo;s website without asking. I used to think about doing street photography, but I&rsquo;m too awkward to approach strangers in public.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>